aywas.com 2019-05-30

# Privacy Policy • Aywas

**Privacy Notice** **Updated May 25, 2018**   
1\. Background  
This privacy notice informs you regarding your personal data given to us and what data we might collect from you, or about you. This applies to all goods and services we offer, and instances that we collect your data.

This privacy notice applies to personal information processed by, or on behalf of, Explorer Games.

2\. Changes to this Privacy Notice

We may change this privacy notice at any time by updating this page in order to comply with any changes in laws or directives that affect our collection or use of your personal data. 

We encourage you to check this page from time to time, however we will make a news post informing you of any changes.

3\. Data Protection Officer

This company is defined as: Explorer Games, 46 Prairie Dr Westmont IL 60559, United States, and we are a data controller of your personal data. We have a dedicated data protection officer (DPO) that you may contact by writing to the below address:

Data Protection Officer  
Explorer Games  
46 Prairie Dr  
Westmont IL 60559  
United States

[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

4\. What personal information do we process?

The personal information we may collect from you is below:

\- Your username  
\- Your e-mail address  
\- Your IP address or mobile phone location data  
\- Your birthday  
\- Your password  
\- Your gender  
\- Records of your contact with us  
\- Products and services you have purchased from us  
\- Your MAC address, if applicable   
\- Your usage of our products and services  
\- Our marketing to you  
\- Your PayPal email, PayPal name, and PayPal shipping address  
\- Any information you post to our website, in private messages, forum posts, or chatrooms

5\. What is the source of this personal information?

\- The majority of personal information is collected from you directly, by inputting the personal information into user settings, website registration, or other website form boxes.  
\- Information generated when you use our products or services

6\. What do we use your personal data for?

We use your personal data, including any data listed under header 4, for the following reasons:

\- providing you the services of the game, for instance requiring your email address to allow you to log into your account  
\- identifying and managing your account on our services  
\- to perform or test the performance of our game, produces, or services  
\- to improve the operation of our business  
\- to follow any guidance to changes of law of governing bodies  
\- to monitor and keep records of you and other users, or you and staff  
\- for market research and analysis of the game  
\- for direct marketing to provide you information about the business's updates or new products or services  
\- to develop new products or services  
\- to facilitate the sale of one or more parts of the business  
\- to process purchases of our goods or services made by you

7\. What are the legal grounds for processing your personal information?

We rely on the following to use your personal data:

a. Where it's needed to provide you with our goods or services, like:  
\- when you register for the game  
\- updating your records  
\- contacting you regarding your account

b. Where it is our legitimate interest to do so, like:  
\- managing your products and services, updating your records  
\- to perform or test performance of our products and services  
\- to carry out monitoring records between you and other users, and you and staff  
\- for market research and analysis  
\- for direct marketing detailing new products or services, or updates to existing products or services

c. To comply with legal obligations  
\- providing your personal information to police, or other governing or legal bodies, by court order or out of concern for your safety

8\. When do we share your personal information with other organizations?

We may share your personal information in the following cases:

\- to our business partners, who are part of providing your products or services, or operating our business  
\- governmental or regulatory bodies, as required by law  
\- police departments, if we feel you are in danger

9\. How can you withdraw your consent?

You may withdraw your consent to use your personal data by contacting at at the below. Please note that we require your personal data to provide an account to you, and that your request requires that your account be permanently deleted. 

Data Protection Officer  
Explorer Games  
46 Prairie Dr  
Westmont IL 60559  
United States

[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

10\. Is your personal information transferred outside the EU? (For EU citizens)

We are based in the US, so by the very nature of the internet, if you provide your personal data to us, it will be transferred out of the EU and into the US servers where our products and services reside. We make sure that suitable safeguards are in place to ensure the safety of your personal information.

11\. What should you do if your personal information changes?

You can update your records in your User Settings, or you may write to us at the below:

Data Protection Officer  
Explorer Games  
46 Prairie Dr  
Westmont IL 60559  
United States

[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

12\. Do you have to provide your personal information to us?

We are unable to provide you with an account on this game, or any of our products and services, if you do not provide certain information to us. If any information is optional, we will make that clear.

13\. Do we monitor the processing of your personal information?

Monitoring means: listening to, recording of, viewing of, intercepting of, or keeping records of calls, email, text messages, social media messages, or other communications.

We may monitor where permitted by law to ensure that our Terms and Conditions and Game Rules are not being broken, as well as to comply with requests by law enforcement or court order. This is done in the interest of your personal safety, in protecting our members and communications systems, and for quality control and staff training.

14\. How long is your personal information retained?

We hold your personal information:  
\- for as long as we have reasonable business needs, like managing your account or our operations  
\- for as long as we provide an account to you, or other goods or services  
\- Retention periods in line with legal and regulatory requirements

15\. What are your rights under the data protection laws?

Here is a list of all of your rights as of May 2018:

\- the right to be informed about your personal information being processed by us  
\- the right to have your personal information corrected if inaccurate, and to have incomplete personal information completed  
\- the right to object to the processing of your personal information  
\- the right to restrict the processing of your personal information  
\- the right to have your personal information erased (right to be forgotten)  
\- the right to request access to your personal information  
\- the right to move, copy, or transfer your personal information

You have the right to complain to the any privacy governing body if you feel your personal information is not processed in accordance with law.

16\. Your right to object

You have to right to object to processing data for direct marketing by clicking the "Unsubscribe" button on direct marketing. You have the right to object to processing other personal data by requesting it to be deleted; if the personal information is necessary to maintain your account, it will require terminating services to you.

17\. Contact Us

If you have questions about this privacy notice, or if you want to exercise your rights to contact our DPO, you can contact us below:

Data Protection Officer  
Explorer Games  
46 Prairie Dr  
Westmont IL 60559  
United States

[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
